<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.9.2" created="2014-09-14 14:53" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Digital Mulling, Marketing &#38; Projects</title>
	<link>http://calumshep.com</link>
	<description>Coffee drinking and scribbles for good measure.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://calumshep.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://calumshep.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>4</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>calum</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>calumshep@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Calum Shepherd]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Calum]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Shepherd]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.2</generator>

	<item>
				<title>The Occupy Flash Campaign</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/occupy-flash-campaign/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=40</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>(This post was previously posted in November 2011. I have now duplicated here for greater reach. To view the original post, please visit the <a title="bigmouthmedia blog" href="http://blog.bigmouthmedia.com/2011/11/22/occupy-flash-unnecessary/">LBi Blog</a>) </em>

<em></em>Denouncing Flash and beginning a campaign to swat its usage, Occupy Flash have received strong coverage in mainstream media. The first thought I had was "is all this really necessary?".

<!--more-->

Shockwave Player launched in 1995, with Flash being made available to download the following year. Launching in a very different digital landscape from the one we see today, under the guise of Macromedia Flash Player. Flash was brought into the limelight with the intention of providing multimedia functionality through web browsers, something that would be sure to impress the surfers of the era.

1996 was not just the year of Flash, it was the year when; Intel launched the the Pentium Processor, where Apple was in the process of going down the pan, and the year the 16MHz Palm Pilot launched - providing computing power on the move. The era now looks a lot like the technology equivalent of the iron age, alas Flash really has lasted the test of time whether people like it or not. I would be inclined to say that Flash was the very beginning of a shift away from traditional software, putting us full steam ahead towards web based deployments mirroring traditional software functionality (think Office 365 – just minus the cloud bit!). Today it is one of the most widely deployed playback technologies ever distributed online.

[caption id="attachment_41" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Adobe-Flash-Saturation-rates.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-41" title="Adobe-Flash-Saturation-rates" alt="adobe flash, occupy flash saturation" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Adobe-Flash-Saturation-rates-300x214.jpg" width="300" height="214" /></a> Adobe Flash Saturation. Currently the study found Flash on the vast majority of internet enabled PC’s, with adoption rates in mature markets reported to be higher than that of Java (According to a Millward Brown survey, July 2011). [/caption]

Flash has provided interesting functionality to a range of different websites. It was always a firm favourite for branded micro sites, providing rich multimedia experiences for visitors. A sole reliance on Flash for web design is in decline, for a number of obvious reasons. However, this has been aided through a well publicised spat between Steve Jobs and Adobe’s pride and joy. This saw a rejuvenated campaign of anti-flash sentiment making itself known amongst the Apple crowd.

Today the desire to adopt HTML5 and CSS3 is front and centre, heralded as a saviour from buggy browsing on the internet. With Adobe announcing the retirement of Flash Lite (mobile), the Occupy Flash campaign and Microsoft’s exclusion from the Windows 8 Metro UI Internet Explorer - the future does indeed look bleak.

It seems industry are putting a focus on Adobe in general, not just Flash. Many articles and commentators have overlooked what Adobe actually provides. As mentioned by Carlous Naxareno within an article on the Thenextweb, Adobe is very much in the business of creating and selling design based tools. With a reaffirmed commitment to develop software that aids the design of HTML5/CSS3 websites, Adobe are on positive track in what could have been a tough time.

Website traffic from mobile devices is constantly on the rise and with a ongoing debate around the absence of Flash on the new Google Phone, it becomes hard to for see continued strong development in this area. However, actively encouraging its downfall seems unnecessary, with a successful outcome only limiting the reach of web based multimedia.

Markers need to be savvy and pick and choose their technologies. This is no different. A campaign against technology is never one I would choose to be a part of.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>40</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-03 14:21:10</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-03 14:21:10</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>occupy-flash-campaign</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[673697451]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>aktt_notify_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[With Occupy Flash in full swing, it raises the question - is all this really necessary?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[occupy-flash-an-unnecessary-step-in-internet-evolution]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_responsive_layout</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>An Approach to Local SEO for Stores</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/local-seo-for-stores/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 14:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=53</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>(This post was previously posted in December 2011 as part of a SEO Advent Calendar series. It has since been amended and updated and reposted here for greater reach. To view the original post, please visit the <a title="bigmouthmedia blog" href="http://blog.bigmouthmedia.com/2011/12/06/no-6-%E2%80%93-seo-advent-calendar/">LBi Blog</a>)</em>

‘Location, Location, Location’ was once a popular show on Channel 4,  now stolen for describing the the importance of local SEO for physical store locations.

<!--more-->

The online visibility of local stores is quite commonly extremely low on many digital marketing managers radars. In turn, it should in fact be key for many online /offline hybrid retailers whom operate brick and motor stores. Retail stores tend to lack the range of products their online counterparts do, with the web acting as a best of breed for everything within the retailer’s portfolio.

Approach local SEO for stores by thinking about location initially  then the the services or products that location actually offers. Loyal customers may just turn up at your store if the need for is time sensitive, or if they just prefer shopping in person. If information on the store is not available online, your customer may either struggle to find it, visit a closed store or even go elsewhere.

<strong>A. Onsite promotion</strong>
Shopping at the last minute is not an alien concept for many at Christmas. In the run up to Christmas, many people will be trawling the internet for details on local stores in a number of scenarios;
<ul>
	<li>The standard delivery window for mail order has expired</li>
	<li>They discover that only expensive ‘next day delivery’ options are available.</li>
	<li>Risk of weather related delivery delays.</li>
</ul>
We can now begin to identify the journey from online to offline customer as being of vital importance as a revenue stream. Thus, make store locations and how to find them visible on site.
<ol>
	<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Promote from the homepage</span></li>
	<li>Provide within your standard navigation, be it a footer or sub-navigation</li>
</ol>
<strong>B. Individual Store Pages</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Guidelines should be in place to ensure all individual store pages provide the most up to date information, so that as changes take place these can be reflected on site.</li>
	<li>Where stores are individually operated or franchised with separate social profiles, think about what social feeds or real time updates you can pull into these pages.</li>
	<li>Customer reviews of that location will be common online, something you wish to include?</li>
	<li>Use easy to remember URL’s.</li>
	<li>Want to take it up a notch? Promote the store landing page from within each location - it may well help create a loyalty aspect that not many other online retailers can match.</li>
</ul>
<strong>C. 3rd Party Location Platforms</strong>
Offsite promotion plays the most important part. Location based platforms such as Google+ Local, Here Places (Nokia), Bing Places and Yelp will transform traffic to location pages in many instances.
<ol>
	<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Be organised and maintain a list of your locations</span></li>
	<li>Claim listings currently out there and close / amend where required</li>
	<li>Build upon this and add new listings, alongside new information as appropriate</li>
	<li><strong>Use link tracking and PROVE it works!</strong></li>
</ol>
Identifying, documenting and maintaining profiles and information contained on 3rd party websites ensures customers do not end up at stores that do not exist, or have since moved after the information was made available. These 3rd party profiles can all be closely integrated with any associated store pages on the 1st party site.

<strong>TLDR;</strong>

Ensure you’re ready for Christmas, update your store pages to truly reflect their offering, promote them on site so they become a viable option for customers AND FINALLY ensure all 3rd party profiles and store details are also up to date. Not everything is this post might be applicable, however throwing some ideas can be the beginnings of a great thing!

<em>Merry Christmas!</em>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>53</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-03 14:32:21</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-03 14:32:21</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>local-seo-for-stores</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="seo-2"><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="social"><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[673694339]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>aktt_notify_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[no]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[An approach to local SEO made easy, helping you identify some of the main areas before putting together a strategy for physical locations.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[seo-store-location-strategy]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_responsive_layout</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Your World Plus Search (Not Search Plus Your World)</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/search-plus-your-world/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=87</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA["Search, Plus your World" has begun rolling out on Google.com for logged in users, which is big news within the industry. Since the launch, we have seen high volumes of coverage, both within the industry and in mainstream media.

<!--more-->

[caption id="attachment_89" align="alignright" width="304"]<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/search-plus-your-world.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-89" title="search-plus-your-world" alt="Search Plus Your World" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/search-plus-your-world.gif" width="304" height="171" /></a> Search Plus Your World, providing rich social oriented results[/caption]

This article discusses the more topical aspects of the update, with their being plenty of excellent advancements for us to shout about in addition to these! If your a little behind on the news front, then the <a href="http://blog.bigmouthmedia.com/2012/01/10/google-gets-even-more-personal-search-your-world/">bigmouthmedia blog</a> does a good job of highlighting the main areas that "Search, plus Your World" impacts, alongside why it is so fundamental.
<h2>Best man gets the best job?</h2>
The changes announced by Google really do represent a fundamental shift in the volume of social oriented content seen on the first page of results. Alongside this, the weighting on the algorithmic process behind them appearing there is also likely to of changed. When personalised search was first introduced many in the industry were up in arms. On going updates then saw closer integration of social content, including profile updates from Twitter. This was designed to give users up to date, topical content on developments as they happened.

It appears that this update really does appear to begin to move Google away from providing results that follow the "best man gets the best job" type analogy. Building upon algorithmic signals that highlight recommended content from friends as being more relevant for you, we see an increased presence of content weighted on what your friends like or discuss. However, there is a clear focus on these being taken from a limited area of the internet in the form of Google+. This a interesting point that has also been raised in a <a href="http://searchengineland.com/examples-google-search-plus-drive-facebook-twitter-crazy-107554">Searchengineland article</a>.
<h2>Do your friends really know best?</h2>
With the first page of results now dominated by personalised results - I've begun to realise that this is great in some scenarios, but not so great in others. When searching for news on a specific subject, I'd like to see the most authoritative source of information, not results heavily weighed by someone Google feels is connected to me (via signals from platforms such as Gmail).

<em>I'd go as far as to say this is "Your World plus Search", not "Search plus Your World".</em>

With a heavily personalised first page and a raft of search results hidden from page two onwards, it does paint a strange picture. I get the impression that this begins to move Google Search towards being a window to the Google Universe first and foremost, whilst being a generic search provider second. Google's main source of revenue is advertising, yet they seem to be impacting results in a big way by pushing a non profit making Google+. In turn, we may well see further paid spend to cover gaps and increased resource devoted towards full bodied Google+ social strategies.
<h2>No matter what, it's great news for Social SEO</h2>
The development of forward thinking social SEO strategies are again in the lime light. Working with social teams to achieve strong coverage, whilst focusing on more traditional aspects such as easy sharing of website content is essential.

It will be interesting to see what direction Google continues to take, with <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-16511794">recent comments from Twitter</a> also highlighting concerns with the new approach. The <a href="http://blog.bigmouthmedia.com/2012/01/10/google-gets-even-more-personal-search-your-world/">bigmouthmedia blog</a> has a nice run through by Simon Hayes, so feel free to check it out as well!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>87</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-11 21:00:13</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-11 21:00:13</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>search-plus-your-world</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[633467079]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Some mullings on what exactly Search, plus Your World means and how it doesn't quite live up to its own elevator pitch.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[your-world-plus-search-not-search-plus-your-world]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>26</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Facebook Fan Page Referrals Decreasing from Search - BMM Blog]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://blog.bigmouthmedia.com/2012/06/11/facebook-fan-page-referrals/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>212.187.249.78</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-06-11 13:22:57</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-06-11 13:22:57</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] from search across multiple engines – an interesting statistic that coincides and expands upon some of my thoughts on Search, plus Your World in January this year.  I highlighted that the increased prominence of a fledgling social network [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>What Does Google Know About Me?</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/google-social-connections/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 11:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=104</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Google rolled out Search, plus Your World to quite a bit of fanfare, mixed opinion and wide ranging commentary a few months ago now. I was very much of the opinion that it was more Your World, plus Search, as opposed to Search, plus Your World. This opinions was formed off the back of having a heavy weighting on Google+ content, social recommendations from friends who you hardly know and more.

<!--more-->

We’ve discussed how Google can associate you with people if you have a Google Account that has Gmail bundled in, with people you regular email, with Google+ accounts, appearing within your results recommending various pieces of content you may be interested in.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/google-social-results.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-105" title="google-social-results" alt="google-social-results" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/google-social-results.png" width="535" height="107" /></a>However, after digging around my profile today I actually discovered how deep this social graph extends. Check out your Dashboard, Available under Accounts &gt; Products &gt; Sign into Dashboard. Upon doing so, scroll down till you see the social connections and content area. Click on “View Social Connections”.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/google-social-connections-main.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-106" title="google-social-connections-main" alt="google-social-connections-main" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/google-social-connections-main.png" width="859" height="165" /></a>Although this isn’t new since Search, plus Your World launched, it does give you an idea how deep the social graph extends. People really are the centre of personalised results.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/google-social-connections.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-107" title="Google Social Connection Details" alt="google-social-connections" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/google-social-connections.png" width="955" height="165" /></a>This should give a good indication as to why our MA Team is so focused on social, social links and social platforms when creating strategies in conjunction with the search teams. Public knowledge for some, some “nice to know” for others. Thoughts? ]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>104</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-03-16 11:11:35</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-03-16 11:11:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>google-social-connections</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[614689100]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Everyone wants to know what Google knows. Now you can, find out how Google connects the dots to find out about you!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Increase Like Button Clicks on Informational Sites</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/increasing-like-button-clicks/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 15:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=121</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>A colleague of mine <a title="Ross Tavendale" href="http://rosstavendale.com/">Ross Tavendale</a> highlighted </strong>the idea of placing social sharing functionality alongside content on informational sites. A great idea for highlighting specific gems likely to be shared, as button placement currently tends to be commonly top / bottom. Some further discussion and a bit of further research this as being a nice little way of potentially increasing the rate at which people interact with social sharing functionality. Essentially what he described is a route to increasing Like Button clicks on informational sites, in turn expanding your visibility and following on Facebook.

<!--more-->

<blockquote><strong>I wanted to find out exactly how this could work, alongside any potential benefits and impact points - this took a little more digging</strong></blockquote>
It is quite common for e-commerce websites to achieve additional Like button clicks through making use of Facebook Open Graph mark-up, declaring products as objects and placing buttons alongside to aid in sharing. This works really well for people thinking about making a purchase, or people about to make a purchase and sharing it to friends and families in advance. <a href="http://www.asos.com">ASOS</a> is a great example of this.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/asos-like-button-example.png"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-128" title="asos-like-button-example" alt="" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/asos-like-button-example-150x150.png" width="150" height="150" /></a>

This e-commerce method works because your single page is a single object, a product. However, how does this work when you are looking to share a specific area of a page on an informational site, without impacting messaging when sharing the page as a whole? This is the aspect that interested me, as I wanted to know how they were pulling it off and if there were any search implications.

Well, let’s take a look at the example Ross initially provided in the form of <a href="http://www.britain-magazine.com/">Britain Magazine</a>.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/brittish-quote-button1.png"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-127" title="brittish-quote-button" alt="" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/brittish-quote-button1-150x150.png" width="150" height="150" /></a>

Britain Magazine increases Facebook Like Button clicks through adding the ability to share quotes on a page out to Facebook. However, the challenge is that you can only make use of one set of Open Graph mark-up per page, meaning that your entire page would have to become about one single quote, even though it will be providing information above and beyond that.
<h2>How do they do it?</h2>
Simple! They use one Like button for the homepage, then on the same page link through to unique URL’s for each quote, with unique, relevant Open Graph mark-up.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/like-button-code-image.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-122" title="like-button-code-image" alt="" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/like-button-code-image.png" width="1137" height="91" /></a>

This means that every quote has its own unique URL, so <strong>you aren’t actually sharing THAT quote, your sharing the same quote but on a different URL</strong> (Something the typical user will never realise). You can see the true URL you are sharing within the iFrame.
<h2>Let’s map this out</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Visitor lands on <a href="http://www.britain-magazine.com/">http://www.britain-magazine.com/</a></li>
	<li>Visitor clicks the like button next to the quote</li>
	<li>Visitor shares <a title="http://www.britain-magazine.com/special-post/quotes/alfred-tennyson/" href="http://www.britain-magazine.com/special-post/quotes/alfred-tennyson/">http://www.britain-magazine.com/special-post/quotes/alfred-tennyson/</a>, a unique URL which only provides a single quote and no other content</li>
</ul>
<h2>GREAT idea, however has multiple impact points</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Google will crawl these URLs, thus for every quote a unique URL may be indexed</li>
	<li>When shared, visitors will arrive on a page with a quote and navigation, not the original section of the homepage where the quote was shared from</li>
	<li>A likely increase in like button clicks for your site's content as a whole</li>
</ul>
Essentially, it provides a good route to increased like button clicks, visibility and brand interaction. Alongside, it potentially provides minimal search value and some indexing issues unless spider controls are used e.g. noindex. <strong>All in all, a great idea! </strong>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>121</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-22 15:18:37</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-22 15:18:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>increasing-like-button-clicks</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="seo-2"><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="social"><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[131]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[659732991]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Want to increase like button clicks? Some great analysis and tips on how to get the most out of placement and positioning! Visit today!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>14</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Calum Shepherd]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://twitter.com/calumshepherd</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>80.193.214.133</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 08:31:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 08:31:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks! If your interested in the social sharing aspect of products on landing pages other than the product page itself, check out the Levis social shopping store. Although not quite to the same extent, it does show how this could transition to other situations / uses.  ]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[507722439]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>13</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[rosstav]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ross.tavendale@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>85.189.177.213</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-23 19:56:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-23 19:56:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Excellent overview Calum. I would be interested to find out the impact of having the liked URL as a landing/ sales page to see if you could start to drive sales via the use of inter linked Facebook like buttons. Surely this should start to become standard practice the same way we interlink the occasional anchor text link on content pages. ]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[507169771]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>16</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Claire]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://twitter.com/techseo</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>80.193.214.133</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 08:45:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 08:45:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi Calum, I think this is a really interesting way of increasing the like button clicks to a page, however, I would definitely be concerned about the impact points that your mention. Particularly the creation of multiple URLs for small snippets of content. Looking at the Britain Magazine example you can see that each of these quote pages reside on almost identical pages. So we would need to consider whether or not we left these pages in the index. The other point I think worth noting is that although there may be increased like button clicks on the page, will we be losing value attributed to that page by search engines, due our rich content being held elsewhere? I suppose if the page itself contains rich content then it shouldn't be an issue, but it's certainly worth careful consideration before implementing. Thanks for a really interesting post!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[507726082]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>17</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Calum Shepherd]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://twitter.com/calumshepherd</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>80.193.214.133</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 12:39:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 12:39:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Claire, thanks for the comment! The impact points are indeed quite a large concern, as you mention they in turn mean that multiple URLs will be created with only small amounts of content. There are already example of the Britain Magazine ones being indexed, as highlighted by Andrew when we discussed internally. 

How to address this really is up for debate, you could potentially link them and use some form of pagination in the form of a quote series. This could be applied in other scenarios as well. That might be a bit controversial though! Thanks]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[507814551]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>18</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Increasing Like Button Clicks on Informational Sites | Inbound.org]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://inbound.org/seo/2012/04/increasing-like-button-clicks-on-informational-sites/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>107.21.245.193</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 14:35:12</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 14:35:12</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Increasing Like Button Clicks on Informational Sites   1 Upvotes   Discuss    Flag    Submitted 1 min ago  Danny Sullivan    SEO calumshepherd.net      Comments [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>19</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Stephen Minto]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.facebook.com/people/Stephen-Minto/100001416377399</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>94.168.189.45</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 14:36:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 14:36:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Maybe you could set up a 301 redirect on the single quote url. So all social traffic would be directed to the original page the person seen the quote on.

Not sure how this would be achieved, assumng the quotes show up at random, I imagine you would need a script that can manage iframes and redirects in real time]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[507897908]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>20</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[SearchCap: The Day In Search, April 24, 2012 | Search Engine Marketing &amp; Website Optimization]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://dynamicmarketingpartners.com/2012/04/searchcap-the-day-in-search-april-24-2012/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>184.168.46.10</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 23:27:33</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 23:27:33</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Increasing Like Button Clicks on Informational Sites, Calum Shepherd [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>21</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[SearchCap: The Day In Search, April 24, 2012 | Market 7]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.market7.co.uk/2012/04/searchcap-the-day-in-search-april-24-2012/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>94.136.40.100</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-25 01:59:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-25 01:59:29</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Increasing Like Button Clicks on Informational Sites, Calum Shepherd [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>22</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[SearchCap: The Day In Search, April 24, 2012 — Greig Oliver Media]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://greigolivermedia.com/blog/searchcap-the-day-in-search-april-24-2012/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>74.54.219.98</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-25 04:27:28</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-25 04:27:28</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Increasing Like Button Clicks on Informational Sites, Calum Shepherd [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>23</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>sandy.kaushalam@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.ydeveloper.com/e-smart-ecommerce-suite.html</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>120.72.91.28</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-25 10:22:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-25 10:22:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Placement is more important for getting more clicks using Like button. The content also plays an important role where it has been placed, like it could be under the text para, image, infographics, video and kind of content that encourage people to like or share.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[508605607]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>24</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[AnthonyDNelson]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>anthony.nelson@swansonhealth.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>76.10.116.216</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-25 18:25:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-25 18:25:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[That example for Britain Magazine is exactly what I think IMDB needs to do for their quote pages. They have a fantastic resource for quotes from TV/Movies that would get a ton more social shares if they marketed it the right way.
]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[508965233]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>25</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Calum Shepherd]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://twitter.com/calumshepherd</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>31.185.155.192</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-25 18:53:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-25 18:53:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks for the comments. Anthony, I agree completely. I've been overwhelmed on a number of occasions by the sheer volume of famous quotes, many of them ones that people would love to share and associate themselves with. ]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[508987675]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>28</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Calum Shepherd]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://twitter.com/calumshepherd</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>80.193.214.133</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-04-24 08:32:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-04-24 08:32:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks! If your interested in the social sharing aspect of products on 
landing pages other than the product page itself, check out the Levis 
social shopping store. Although not quite to the same extent, it does 
show how this could transition to other situations / uses.   ]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[507722506]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Is Structured Data Prioritised over Search Intent?</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/structured-data-search-intent/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 15:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=141</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Semantic Web is an interesting concept, fuelled from a desire to be able to establish set identifiers for information on the internet. The end goal of structuring unstructured data on the internet is an ambitious one, which I don’t think will ever totally come to fruition in its current form. Turning the internet into the equivalent of a giant database is great, but will need wide spread support within HTML5 and via CMS creators.

<!--more-->

<blockquote>“The Semantic Web is a collaborative movement led by the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) [1] that promotes common formats for data on the World Wide Web. By encouraging the inclusion of semantic content in web pages, the Semantic Web aims at converting the current web of unstructured documents into a "web of data".” – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web">Wikipedia</a></blockquote>
With the Wall Street Journal highlighting a renewed focus in this area for Google (as reported by <a href="http://searchengineland.com/wsj-says-big-google-search-changes-coming-reality-check-time-115227">Search Engine Land</a>), it again raises questions about search engines use of this semantic data. Webmasters and marketers adopt semantic web mark-up to help make the proposition possible, in turn dedicating their own resource and time.  Google has long strived to be able to use this data effectively, pretty much one of their long term goals in fact. This approach could stem as far back as when Google began to provide search results for synonyms, as opposed to results for an exact match of the search query used.
<h2>Search intent considerations</h2>
The interesting part for me is that searcher intent seems to be a bit of an afterthought when using data from the semantic web. Take football as a prime example. Within the UK football scores are returned regularly for top level queries around recent / current matches. This would see me search for “Celtic v Rangers” and I would be fed back the current score via aggregated sources. This is a mixed blessing, as at this stage we don’t actually know what information the searcher was looking for.
<h2>The great “semantic search” swindle</h2>
Alongside this, there is the on-going concern that as people are adding structured mark-up on site, Google is taking more and more of this information, whilst providing little in return. The whole experience of search is based around getting the most relevant, insightful content and being able to either narrow your search down, or browse through a number of sites to build a general opinion on the given subject. As any University project will tell you, multiple sources are always better than a single source; with structured data you’re losing the personal aspect of peoples “opinions” on the subject, instead having them grouped together in a “one best answer” approach.

Whilst not applicable in all instances, it is certainly something worth thinking about. The advancement of this area of Google’s game is definitely an exciting one. People will again have to innovate to ensure they see any form of benefit from it.  I would ask;
<blockquote><strong>“Are we prioritising structured data over search intent?”</strong></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>141</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-28 15:19:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-28 15:19:27</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>structured-data-search-intent</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="seo-2"><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[667771444]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[With the push towards structured data in full swing, is this being prioritised over what people are truly looking for?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Yelp Edinburgh’s Winterfall Wonderland @ Ghillie Dhu</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/yelp-edinburgh-ghillie-dhu/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 09:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/blog/?p=150</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I recently had the pleasure of attending a Yelp! Edinburgh event in an official capacity as part of my role at VisitScotland. The aim was to learn about the community, what the events are all about and how we can potentially work with each other moving forward.

<!--more-->

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/yelp-winterfall-wonderland-ghillie-dhu.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-151" title="yelp-winterfall-wonderland-ghillie-dhu" alt="" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/yelp-winterfall-wonderland-ghillie-dhu-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a>

The event was titled Winterfall Wonderland and was hosted at Ghillie Dhu Edinburgh. The evening was truly fantastic, with some excellent businesses and Yelpers turning up. The way these events showcase some of the fantastic produce on offer, whilst getting people excited about visiting local business is truly commendable.

Attendees seemed engaged throughout, whilst the ever apparent social updates were in full flow. An excellent example of how physical events are so lovingly communicated and promoted online whilst the event is in full swing.

You can read all about it via my write up on the <a href="http://twitter.com/visitscotland">@VisitScotland</a> blog.

<a href="http://www.visitscotland.com/blog/cities/yelp-winterfall-wonderland-ghillie-dhu/">Yelp Edinburgh’s Winterfall Wonderland @ Ghillie Dhu</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>150</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-11-22 09:30:36</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-11-22 09:30:36</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>yelp-edinburgh-ghillie-dhu</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[938929042]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Yelp Edinburgh’s Winterfall Wonderland @ Ghillie Dhu]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[View a overview of the Yelp Edinburgh event that was held @ Ghillie Dhu, Edinburgh. A fantastic evening in one of Edinburgh's hottest venues! Visit today!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yelp-edinburghs-winterfall-wonderland-ghillie-dhu]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Google Adwords Certification Study Guides (Fundamentals / Advanced)</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/google-adwords-study-guides/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/?p=199</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>Updated: 15/01/2014 (Google Partners Program)</em>

Looking to expand your Adwords knowledge? Whether or not you actually manage Adwords campaigns, an understanding of how they work and paid media terminology in general is always going to be a benefit to you. <a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/adwords-qualified-professional.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-206 alignright" alt="google adwords certification study guide" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/adwords-qualified-professional.jpg" width="126" height="126" /></a>

A lot of people will thus look to Google Exams to help with this, as they bundle revision with certification. To help with this, I've listed some Google Adwords Certification study guides that may aid in getting you through both the Fundamental and Advanced Search exams.

<!--more-->

It is perfectly possible to pass your Google Adwords exam without the need for physical guides or online revision packages. However if you do need some additional reading or would like something for your desk, check this book <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/1118115619/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=6738&amp;creativeASIN=1118115619&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=calsheblo-21">Google AdWords For Dummies - Amazon</a>.

Introducing <strong>Google Partners program - things have now changed. </strong>
<ul>
	<li>Google Partner Exams are now free! This means you don't need to pay for your Adwords exams anymore.</li>
	<li>The new Google Partners website is designed to allow you to revise and sit the exams, all via one portal.</li>
	<li>Resources from 3rd parties tend to be out of date and don't match the current Google Adwords Interface, nor the exam material. They do still provide value however and will no doubt be updated post launch of Google Partners.</li>
	<li>Google resources are at times a different from the interface, however you can bank on the Google material matching the exam.</li>
</ul>
In short, things are become a whole lot more clean when it comes to revision resources.  Digging around for Google Adwords Certification study guides for your Fundamentals / Advanced Search exams is far less important post Google Partners launch.

&nbsp;

<strong>1. Official Google Study Guides</strong>

The Google Partners area provides all the initial steps to get you up and running. You will be able to access to seminars, study guides and much more. Essential for you kicking off your Google Adwords Certification study.

Visit the <a href="https://support.google.com/partners/topic/3204437?hl=en-GB&amp;ref_topic=3111012">Google Partners Help Area</a>

Download the <a href="https://support.google.com/partners/answer/3045820?hl=en-GB">Google Adwords Fundementals Study Guide (PDF)</a>

Download the <a href="https://support.google.com/partners/answer/3045822?hl=en-GB">Google Adwords Search Advanced Study Guide (PDF)</a>

&nbsp;

<strong>2. Google Adwords Help Centre </strong>

Provides help resources for terminology and a run through ranging from basic setup and basics to billing. A strong resource for referencing as opposed to studying for your exam directly.

Visit the <a href="http://support.google.com/adwords/">Google Adwords Help Centre</a>.

&nbsp;

<strong>3. Google Adwords Interface </strong>

The Adwords interface will give you the best exposure possible help for you to pass your exam. You will need a valid Google account alongside a name, address and credit card. Don't worry, you can remove your card once you are setup.

The real value is assigning budgets and getting some campaigns live. Google regularly provide vouchers of around $50 to new customers via email to get people up and running, so look out for these in the days after activation. The Adwords Coupon page is also useful and currently has £75 free for a £25 spend <em>(Confirmed live Jan 2014)</em>.

Visit the <a href="http://www.google.co.uk/adwords/coupons/">Google Adwords Coupon Website</a>.

Visit the <a href="http://adwords.google.co.uk">Google Adwords Website</a>.

<strong style="line-height: 1.5em;">4. Google YouTube Adwords Playlist</strong>

Various videos on anything and everything Adwords. You can find a specific playlist for all the introductory videos for adwords via the link below.

Visit the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLD30CBD9BA34712EA">Google YouTube Adwords Overview Playlist</a>.

<strong>5. Other Websites</strong>
Please note, these are additional resources are pretty out of date. However they do provide a bit more context for you if you have additional study time available.
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/thejargroup/google-adwords-study-guide-how-to-pass-the-adwords-test">Slideshare Slide Deck</a> by Emily Liedblad</li>
	<li><a href="http://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2011/02/10/adwords-certification-tips">General Certification Guide</a> by Tom Demers</li>
	<li><a href="http://www.quia.com/quiz/2779973.html">Quiz </a>from Mr McSheeny</li>
</ul>
I would also recommend downloading the free uCertify trial, as they do offer an extremely robust package with a decent number of questions available for free.

Good luck and let me know how you get on with your Google Adwords study!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>199</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-01-15 15:45:54</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-01-15 15:45:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>google-adwords-study-guides</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[72]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Google Adwords Study Guide]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Google Adwords Cerfitifcation Study Gudes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Get some Google Adwords study under your belt. View the best resources for the Google Adwords Fundamentals & Advanced Search Exams. Visit today!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[996971931]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>29</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Nhinquattran]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>nhinquattran@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>118.70.131.15</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-02-07 07:32:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-02-07 07:32:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I can help you guys pass google adwords exams to get certification in case you don't have time to study all the materials
Drop me a pm to my gmail: nhinquattran]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[791556741]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>31</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Arpit Singhi]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>arpitsinghi@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>59.182.95.170</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-04-27 23:19:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-04-27 23:19:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[stuck with 94% and 95% and idea folks where its getting wrong

http://www.starttest.com/9.0.0.0/transcriptview.aspx?r=1&amp;code=I006FFE70016DF17CFD6EF77C0167EE65D14DE3]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[878146180]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>34</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Eugene]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>sidewinder2057@rambler.ru</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>213.197.165.46</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-06-18 14:47:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-06-18 14:47:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Great collection of preparation tips! For all you out there planning to take Adwords exam, you can take some AdWords Fundamentals practice tests for free at http://teachmegood.com. There's also an exam simulation mode which allows you to simulate the real exam experience. And it's cheap - only $12!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[934290588]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>42</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Ngo Ngan]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>nhinquattran@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>222.254.52.179</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-10-09 17:05:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-10-09 17:05:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[You can check my result here: https://googlerecords.starttest.com?code=I0069F15FFB75F7640861EA64F97CF4620B39EA11

I can help you guys pass these exams to get the Adwords certification fastly without studying

Drop me a pm to my gmail: nhinquattran

I can pass Analytics IQ test also]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1076504527]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>44</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Anriana Clissa]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>adrianaclissa@yahoo.ca</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>122.168.50.140</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-01-15 10:11:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-01-15 10:11:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[75GB  7UQHC-GNETV-EJX7 Adwords Coupon credit free for beginners by FreeVouch]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1201560960]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>45</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Helen Brown]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>helen@ipassexam.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.ipassexam.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>88.144.2.192</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-01-22 15:09:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-01-22 15:09:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks for the great tips, but could I also add that a bit of pre exam testing will also help.  We have sample exam questions that cover all of the syllabus from the Fundamentals to Search to Display.  It definitely helps to use mock exams, it does give you a good idea on how the exam is going to go.  http://www.ipassexam.com]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1211996783]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>47</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Ngo Ngan]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>nhinquattran@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>118.70.131.15</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-02-27 07:59:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-02-27 07:59:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[You can check my result here: http://www.starttest.com/9.0.0.0/transcriptview.aspx?r=1&amp;code=I0069F15FFB75F7640861EA64F97CF4620B39EA11 



I can help you guys pass these exams to get the Adwords certification fastly 

Drop me a pm to my gmail: nhinquattran 

I can pass Analytics IQ test also!@!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1262631072]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>The Definition of SEO in 2013</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/definition-of-seo/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 20:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/?p=210</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Digital moves quickly. This time of year frequently sees a wealth of blog and industry news focused on one aspect of this, SEO. Camps tend to joust for attention and kudos, producing link bait focused articles which aim to foretell the future. Posts are either plain misguided, or quite notable pieces that are worthy of the coverage they receive. Unfortunately on many occasions its the first of the two that is true, with said articles being poorly promoted with overly optimised headings and content.

<!--more-->

Some commentary on the subject and pieces in question;
<ul>
	<li><strong>The definition of SEO depends upon the individual</strong>, with algorithm changes and thought leaders driving definitions</li>
	<li><strong>SEO has evolved</strong> from a "one man know it all show" to something which requires delegation of key aspects to multiple teams - both technical and business oriented</li>
	<li>The <strong>SEO industry has grown its marketing legs</strong>, with a lot of traditional gurus from technical backgrounds now competing for roles with traditional marketers who have adapted to digital (alongside digital fresh faces)</li>
	<li><strong>The organisation defines the role</strong> in many instances. A small company can see an SEO manager take on multiple roles including content production. In a large organisation coordination becomes far more important, with the role being one of synergy across teams</li>
	<li>The breadth of modern, sustainable SEO has seen a lot of <strong>people come and go from the industry</strong> - of whom the vast majority will all end up working in a role that they encompassed to some extent during their time in SEO (Project Management, UX, Content Marketing etc)</li>
	<li>Many <strong>SEOs attempt to redefine their role</strong>. The truth is, no matter how you describe your current position - true SEO now encompasses a lot of the unpaid digital spectrum - thus is something to be extremely proud of</li>
</ul>
The industry has changed, the definition has changed and the people have changed - its a form of natural evolution. No matter whether your strengths are routed in technical understanding or marketing prowess, you can still excel as both are still vastly important.
<blockquote>"If SEO is dead, then so is TV. Definitions change and much like TV isn't just about Mad Men era adverts anymore (just look at product placement), SEO isn't just about its traditional roots. The only difference is adverts didn't die, meta keywords did"</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">What doesn't die is an evolving strategy, it adapts and innovations - that's pretty much what SEO should be defined as. A modern digital strategy which encompasses many digital marketing elements. It is an exciting time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>210</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-01-10 20:57:19</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-01-10 20:57:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>definition-of-seo</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="project-management"><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="seo-2"><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="social"><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The phrase "SEO is dead" rolls my eyes like no other. SEO should be defined as an evoling strategy encompassing marketing elements - find out why!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1018846228]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[seo-is-dead-the-neverending-story]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[commentary-on-commentary-seo]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>49</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Shiela Harpole]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://marketplace.pepdeal.com/shop/social-networking-promotion/73-facebook-fans-.html</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>188.68.255.136</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-04-26 22:21:27</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-04-26 22:21:27</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[<strong>Shiela Harpole You can increase Facebook Fans by arranging Contests,like-gated Coupons/ebooks,Facebook Sponsored ads or adding a “Like” button or box to your blog. These ways are good but take much time to increase fan count.If you want Facebook fans&#8230;</strong>

You can increase Facebook Fans by arranging Contests,like-gated Coupons/ebooks,Facebook Sponsored ads or adding a “Like” button or box to your blog. These ways are good but take much time to increase fan count.If you want Facebook fans fast, you should&#8230;]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>trackback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Project Management &amp; Digital Marketers</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/digital-project-management/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 12:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/?p=280</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Digital Project Management is common place in large organisations and businesses throughout the UK. Loosely speaking roles can encompass the web development, infrastructure management or wider digital marketing campaigns. There is massive potential for the fundamentals of project management to be harnessed and applied to our wider digital marketing roles, improving efficiency and the ability for people to correctly measure success.

<!--more-->

<strong>What about creativity? </strong>

Working in the digital industry at the moment, especially in SEO, will see you bombarded with information on the importance of content led creative. "How to get creative", "how to make the most out of content marketing", "tips on the value marketing proposition" - the list is endless. All are well and good and creativity should indeed take centre stage - don't get me wrong. It is essential modern digital marketers are creative, however organisation and good planning is right up there as well, no question!

<strong>Why being organised matters </strong>

It's simple, the more organised you are the better you can manage your own work, the work of your team and your ability to convey results (<em>success!</em>). As a granular example, the concept of backing up is lost recently in a lot of peoples minds. With always on cloud services and web apps giving the impression that their data will always be available, its no surprise. In many instances it will, in others it won't. Take Google Webmaster Tools, if your not exporting it then after 3 months your search query data disappears. This can create awkward moments whereby you don't have the data you need to measure success / performance - thus poor planning and documenting leads to an inability to measure success.

In addition, version control for documentation is also important. Although a strange concept for many outside projects and development, it can play an essential part of having people contribute to working documents on the fly - without loosing anything in the process. Thus, if you need to roll back due to one of the team being on a different level, then you can!

<strong>Some quick tips
</strong>
<ol>
	<li><strong>Familarise;</strong> Read up on both Prince2 and Agile methodologies, as learning the fundamentals will change your mindset before starting up</li>
	<li><strong>Big Picture;</strong> Think about the bigger picture; what are you aiming to achieve, what is the ideal end result and how will you measure success</li>
	<li><strong>Planning &amp; Communication;</strong> Plan properly and communicate it and your progress clearly, it's better to initially include to many people than to little. Make sure you establish who the stakeholders are!</li>
	<li><strong>Scope;</strong> If you feel that something is spiraling or is suffering from scope creep; take a step back, identify whether or not you can accommodate, reject / accept the additional ideas. You can also speak to a PM in your organisation for a second opinion</li>
	<li><strong>Risks &amp; Issues;</strong> Document any on-going risks or issues as they occur, its better to see these early and justify them once they have taken place</li>
</ol>
<strong>TLDR;</strong> Remember the fundamentals of Prince2 project management and <strong>BE MORE PRODUCTIVE!</strong> You'll have well documented benefits and kudos from those around you for doing so. You don't need to enter documentation hell (although many do) - you can use all the above and still be nimble.

You can check out the <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0113311990/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=0113311990&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=calsheblo-21">Prince2 Pocketbook</a> if you want to find out more, a worthwhile read and its short enough to actually be practical and useful.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>280</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-05-02 12:51:20</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-05-02 12:51:20</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>digital-project-management</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="project-management"><![CDATA[Project Management]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Project Management is now engrained in digital, with dedicated roles created. However, you can be a smarter marketer by picking up the basics! Learn more.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1290539500]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_responsive_layout</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[digital-project-management-tips]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[project-management-digital-marketers]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>38</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[google]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://images.google.com.hk</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.31.40.116</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-07-02 21:13:05</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-07-02 21:13:05</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[<strong>google...</strong>

G http://images.google.com.hk/...]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>trackback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>46</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Spook SEO]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>spookseo@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>180.149.31.149</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-02-05 08:17:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-02-05 08:17:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[<!-- br {mso-data-placement:same-cell;} -->Hello Calum!

This is such a very interesting post. Thank you for sharing. I totally agree with you that the more organised we are, the better we can really manage our own work, the work of our team and our ability to bring results.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1231584358]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Google Databoard Custom Infographic Creation</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/google-databoard/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 17:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/?p=341</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Whilst mulling over the available Google Webinar events that are available in the next few months - something stood out. A session devoted to <strong>Google Databoard</strong> is available, titled "<a href="http://www.google.com/think/webinars/custom-infographics-databoard.html">Creating Custom Infographics with the New Google Databoard</a>".
<h2><strong>What is Google Databoard?</strong></h2>
Based upon the description it becomes clear early on - a new tool that offers people the ability to build infographics, making use of Google data. The benefits for advertisers and marketers is easy clear; robust, trustworthy statistics in a digestible format. Google on the other hand gets good brand awareness and more justification as to the importance of Search and Display. They will no doubt let the statistics speak for themselves in this regard.

<!--more-->

<h2><strong>What does it look like?</strong></h2>
<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Google-Databoard-Infographic-Builder.png"><img class="size-large wp-image-342 alignleft" alt="Google Databoard Infographic Builder" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Google-Databoard-Infographic-Builder-1024x555.png" width="652" height="353" /></a>

A colleague Paul Bruce spotted that it is already live, however we are not sure if it is meant to be accessible. You can;

Find the main landing page and <a href="http://bynd-data-board-dev.appspot.com/">try it out here</a>. Or, you can check out some <a href="http://bynd-data-board-dev.appspot.com/theme/1/">example studies available</a> for you to try here.

I would recommend you signup for the <a href="http://vshow.on24.com/vshow/learnwebinars">Google Webinar</a> however.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Google-Databoard-Example-Studies.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-352" alt="Google Databoard Example Studies" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Google-Databoard-Example-Studies-300x164.png" width="300" height="164" /></a><a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Google-Databoard-Build-Your-Infographic.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-351" alt="Google Databoard Build Your Infographic" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Google-Databoard-Build-Your-Infographic-300x160.png" width="300" height="160" /></a>

<strong>Give it a look and let me know what you think! If you liked this, please share this post!</strong>
<h3><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Update</strong></span></h3>
This has now been announced in the most recent Google Webinar! Joy Hawkins posted a couple of shots from the demo, viewable on the <a href="http://localsearchforum.catalystemarketing.com/internet-marketing/8439-new-google-databoard.html">Catalystemarketing forum</a>. Both images courtesy of Joy.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/google-databoard-Infographic2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-378" alt="google-databoard-Infographic2" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/google-databoard-Infographic2-300x144.jpg" width="300" height="144" /></a> <a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/google-databoard-Infographic3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-379" alt="google-databoard-Infographic3" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/google-databoard-Infographic3-300x144.jpg" width="300" height="144" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>341</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-06-12 17:14:00</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-06-12 17:14:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>google-databoard</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-gallery"><![CDATA[Gallery]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Some mulling over available Google Webinar events saw something stand out - a session devoted to Google Databoard. Find out what Google Databoard is!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_opengraph-description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Some mulling over available Google Webinar events saw something stand out - a session devoted to Google Databoard. Find out what Google Databoard is!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_google-plus-description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Some mulling over available Google Webinar events saw something stand out - a session devoted to Google Databoard. Find out what Google Databoard is!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1394892387]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[google-databoard-custom-infographic-creation]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>35</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[brendan chiu]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>shinobi_drk@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>100.43.215.18</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-06-27 18:52:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-06-27 18:52:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Any images of the actual data visualizations you can share?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[944427450]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>36</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[VM]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>matt@visualmarvel.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>173.167.99.61</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-06-28 21:34:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-06-28 21:34:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[None of the links are working? I did get to check out Googles Webinar about it though @ http://www.google.com/think/webinars/custom-infographics-databoard.html though so looks like you stumbled on it pre-release.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[945767568]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>37</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[caludnet]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>calumshep@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>146.90.236.51</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2013-06-28 22:53:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2013-06-28 22:53:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Indeed, it was a pre-release beta they had up and running. No screenshots of the actual studies unfortunately, as they were not available. I missed the Webinar, so hoping to catch this later in the week and get the full low down!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_parent_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>dsq_post_id</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[945835048]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>TheDigitals 2013 Shortlist for VisitScotland</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/the-digitalsshortlist/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/?p=384</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Some good news! Although a little late in highlighting, the digital team at VisitScotland were shortlisted for an <a href="http://thedigitalsawards.com/">E-Consultancy #TheDigitals Travel &amp; Tourism</a> award, back in May 2013.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/the-digitals-logo.png"><img alt="The Digitals Logo" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/the-digitals-logo.png" width="300" height="103" /></a>

Our campaign was focused around Shetland Ponies in Cardigans, one which saw solid work from our PR team and some great content production to make it a success. Results were quality search positions for related terms, TV features in the US and on-going engagement on social media. We are still seeing a continued flow of traffic to our blog post on the ponies. The post continues to be the most successful single page we have ever put live on our .COM.

<!--more-->

The ponies were fresh, creative and an excellent example of cross-team collaboration.

The US TV spot on CNN is included below.

<iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/PfaRtzDNePc" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>

Unfortunately we didn't win on the night, but a good result none the less for the organisation!

Check out the original <a href="http://www.visitscotland.com/blog/scotland/shetland-ponies-in-cardigans/">Shetland Ponies Blog Post</a> over @ the VisitScotland blog.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>384</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-07-24 18:00:03</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-07-24 18:00:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-digitalsshortlist</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="social"><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[TheDigitals 2013 Shortlist for VisitScotland]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The digital team @VisitScotland were shortlisted for an E-Consultancy #TheDigitals Travel & Tourism award. Find out more!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1527416619]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[385]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Turing Festival 2013 Highlights</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/turing-festival-2013/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 11:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshepherd.net/?p=431</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I was lucky enough to attend the <a href="http://turingfestival.com/">Turing Festival</a> in Edinburgh on the 24th and 25th August 2013. Turing took place over a 2 day period towards the tail of the <a href="http://www.edinburghfestivals.co.uk/">Edinburgh Festival</a>, meaning the city was still in top form. The talks were diverse and interesting, with many speakers using technology as a foundation, as opposed to being the subject itself. This made the festival feel more dynamic, interesting and engaging than your run of the mill event. 

<!--more-->

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/turing-festival-image.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-448" alt="Turing Festival Image" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/turing-festival-image-300x223.jpg" width="300" height="223" /></a>

<strong>Talks Attended @ Turing Festival 2013</strong>
<ul>
	<li>Five Startups go mad in Edinburgh</li>
	<li>Future of Money</li>
	<li>Digital Distribution</li>
</ul>
<ul>
	<li>Digital Marketing &amp; Growth Hacking</li>
	<li>Festival Keynote by Neil Stephenson</li>
	<li>Future of Music</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

<strong>Future of Money Highlights;</strong>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://www.iabuk.net/people/sandra-alzetta"><strong>Sandra Alzetta</strong></a> from Visa gave a extremely grounded speech. She placed a large focus on mobile payments on smartphones, alongside contactless plastic cards. She was keen to highlight the future is both mobile AND plastic, with each having a place in the Visa vision of the future of payments.</li>
	<li><a href="http://plan99.net/~mike/#top"><strong>Mike Hearn</strong></a> from Bitcoin (and Google)'s speech had to be one of the highlights of the festival. Mike's talk was extremely wide ranging, featuring Google driverless cars and explaining a potential bleak outlook for anyone who doesn't work in the creative sector. He presented a vision for the future focused on a TradeNet and it's autonomous agents - all removing the need for human involvement in more manual, repetitive tasks. A future where machines will run their own businesses, competing in a marketplace against each other for human business. A fascinating insight! He also mentioned some background and ideology on Bitcoin, but this was really overshadowed by everything that preceded it.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">Social reviews don't make that much sense, says Mike Hearn of Google. Lots of spam and strangers. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23turingfest&amp;src=hash">#turingfest</a>

— Andrew Girdwood (@AndrewGirdwood) <a href="https://twitter.com/AndrewGirdwood/statuses/370910677512486912">August 23, 2013</a></blockquote>
&nbsp;
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">The future of money by Visa Europe. Trust. Completely agree. Money doesn't do public betas <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23turingfest&amp;src=hash">#turingfest</a> CC <a href="https://twitter.com/NJones">@NJones</a>

— Calum Shepherd (@calumshepherd) <a href="https://twitter.com/calumshepherd/statuses/370908903141543936">August 23, 2013</a></blockquote>
&nbsp;
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">Visa Europe forecast 50% of their transactions by 2020 will be mobile. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23turingfest&amp;src=hash">#turingfest</a>

— Calum Shepherd (@calumshepherd) <a href="https://twitter.com/calumshepherd/statuses/370903909248028672">August 23, 2013</a></blockquote>
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async=""></script><strong>Digital Distribution Highlights;</strong>
<ul>
	<li>The highlight of the digital distribution talks had to be <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dj-powers/67/70/495"><strong>DJ Powers from Valve</strong></a>. He gave insight into the eco-system of Steam and their recent developments in community contribution. <a href="http://www.teamfortress.com/">Team Fortress 2 </a>is one of their most recent success stories, seeing a marketplace built out around digital products and official community updates - launched for the entire player base. A success story included a hat seller (for in-game characters) who achieved 6 digit profits for his creations.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">Team Fortress Community Update biggest grossing hour for them after launch. Awesome. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23turingfest&amp;src=hash">#turingfest</a>

— Calum Shepherd (@calumshepherd) <a href="https://twitter.com/calumshepherd/statuses/370945261469986816">August 23, 2013</a></blockquote>
&nbsp;

<strong>Digital Marketing &amp; Growth Hacking</strong>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://emphaticsolutions.com/"><strong>Brian Doll from Github</strong></a> was first up, reinforcing the need for great marketing to follow a simple philosophy <strong>"Build Something, Tell People"</strong>. An interesting concept that caused split opinion in regards to how easy this is to implement in a large scale organisation. None the less, an ideal that everyone should aspire to. Plus, he had a great animated GIF used across both his presentations!</li>
	<li><a href="http://blog.arhg.net/"><strong>Andrew Girdwood</strong></a>, a former colleague from my time agency side, was presenting his thoughts on the future of digital. A compelling presentation covering native content, examples on how companies are now founded around video seeding / testing and mobile real time bidding.</li>
	<li><a href="http://confusedofcalcutta.com/about-me/"><strong>JP Rangaswami</strong></a> from Salesforce was quite inspiring. I didn't manage to take any notes from the talk, but came away throughly impressed with his ability to tell stories and bring the audience with him on a journey through technology.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">"Living infographics". Steven Drost from Stipso explains how text can become more than a sum of its parts. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23turingfest&amp;src=hash">#turingfest</a>

— Calum Shepherd (@calumshepherd) <a href="https://twitter.com/calumshepherd/statuses/371204304608456704">August 24, 2013</a></blockquote>
&nbsp;
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>&quot;Focus on tribes. Focus on communities that already exist&quot; Brian Doll from <a href="https://twitter.com/github">@github</a> <a href="http://t.co/TJ1AJGnNwZ">pic.twitter.com/TJ1AJGnNwZ</a></p>&mdash; Calum Shepherd (@calumshepherd) <a href="https://twitter.com/calumshepherd/statuses/371198273882980352">August 24, 2013</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
If you would like to find out more, check out the <a href="http://turingfestival.com/">Turing Festival website</a>.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>431</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-08-26 11:19:40</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-08-26 11:19:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>turing-festival-2013</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="seo-2"><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="social"><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="technology"><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="thoughts"><![CDATA[Thoughts &amp; Commentary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Turing Festival 2013 was held in Edinburgh this year, towards the end of the festival. Summaries of the talks, group discussions and more.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_post_restored_from</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:20:"restored_revision_id";i:453;s:16:"restored_by_user";i:4;s:13:"restored_time";i:1377515855;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Nestle &amp; Google Android KitKat Announcement</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/nestle-google-announcement/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 12:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshep.com/?p=507</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hot off the press this morning was the news that Nestle and Google have forged a partnership, branding the new version of Android KitKat. You can read more on the background of the announcement on the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-23926938">BBC News</a> website.

<!--more-->

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Screen-Shot-2013-09-04-at-12.44.04.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-493" alt="Screen Shot 2013-09-04 at 12.44.04" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Screen-Shot-2013-09-04-at-12.44.04-268x300.png" width="268" height="300" /></a>

Currently knee deep in website migrations myself, I began to ask myself if their overhaul of the consumer <a href="http://www.kitkat.com/">http://www.kitkat.com/</a> website had been well thought through, or just a bit of an after thought. Huge coverage for both brands in online and offline media was the main goal, but what about the overall site experience for people arriving at the KitKat website from search? Unfortunately at this early stage it is an experience riddled with broken links.

The Google search results screenshot highlights results serving 404s, alongside links to different locale versions that have no practical use on the newly relaunched website. In addition, the legacy WAP site is redirecting for a homepage query, but any lower level pages result in 404s.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/google-nestle-seo-image.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-490" alt="Google Nestle Broken Links" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/google-nestle-seo-image.png" width="692" height="468" /></a>

With this said, it is a fantastic design &amp; build, with some crazy creativity to make this happen on the part of both Google &amp; Nestle. The results have seen some crazy coverage online, with plenty of links for both parties (not that they need them!).

If anyone has any of the Android KitKat chocolates, feel free to pop them over to the office - I'm here all week =)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>507</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-09-04 12:54:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-09-04 12:54:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>nestle-google-announcement</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Nestle & Google Android, Kit-Kat Announcement]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Google have decided to partner with Nestle on the naming of the new version of the Andorid operating system.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1708935250]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[490]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Attendance @ Jump Digital Marketing Event</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/attendance-jump-digital-marketing-event/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 15:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshep.com/?p=513</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I had the pleasure of attending the <a href="http://festivalofmarketing.com/jump">Jump digital marketing event</a> in London yesterday, as part of the E-Consultancy <a href="http://festivalofmarketing.com/">Festival of Marketing</a>. Jump is all about creating a joined up consumer experience. Talks ranged from user experience to psychology and its impact on digital marketing, a real mix of extremely interesting and thought provoking topics.

<a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/jump-festival-of-marketing.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-524 alignright" alt="Jump Festival of Marketing" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/jump-festival-of-marketing-300x224.jpg" width="300" height="224" /></a>

<strong>Up close and personal, engaging your target audience anytime, anywhere</strong> - <a href="http://www.expedia.co.uk/"><strong>Expedia</strong></a>
<ul>
	<li>Made an early and accelerated move to mobile via an acquisition. The team worked relatively independently of the main organisation in a separate physical location (San Francisco). The result? They moved quickly and freely in many instances from their central head office in Seattle - driving forward their mobile offering in a relatively short period of team.</li>
	<li>Expedia identified early on that responsive design wasn't the best choice or their objectives, as they felt the ability to create unique experiences for difference screensizes / and usage enviroments trumped all other considerations.</li>
	<li>Positioning mobile prominently was important for them, integrating it in with internal KPIs and offering unique deals to consumers.</li>
	<li>TV campaigns are built around their mobile offering, with dedicated ads produced to highlight unique functionality and features.</li>
	<li>Optimisation does not live on traditional search channels anymore. A focus needs to be paid to presentation within mobile app stores. This includes icons, descriptions, reviews and driving downloads.</li>
</ul>
<!--more-->
<strong>More channels, more opportunities, delivering personalised service in a digital world</strong> -<strong> <a href="https://www.americanexpress.com/uk/">American Express</a></strong>
<ul>
	<li>Some huge partnerships for American Express over the last couple of years. A fascinating take away from the Facebook partnership; the majority of card holders who synced their details with Facebook had actually opted out of email communication from the organisation.</li>
	<li>Their newest TripAdvisor partnership involves checking payment histories to confirm reviews are by people who have actually stayed at the venue - extremely interesting review trust indicator.</li>
	<li>Others partnerships included Xbox Live (Game progress / rewards) and Twitter (Tweet to buy, Tweet for discount).</li>
	<li>Cultural change within the organisation a big focus, with importance placed upon people using the digital platforms the organisation is trying to drive forward. Others important areas included revisiting internal guidelines, throwing away job titles for brainstorming, simplifying processes and encouraging a start up ethos operating under the company philosophy.</li>
</ul>
<strong>How to improve conversion</strong> - <strong><a href="http://www.redeye.com/">RedEye</a> <a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/RedEye-MarkPatronJumpPresentation09102013.pdf">(DOWNLOAD)</a></strong>
<ul>
	<li>Statistics galore from this white paper overview. Due to the amount of statistics and the presentation being publicly available in the near future, I'll refrain from sharing specific stats, but will however hopefully update this post with a link once available.</li>
	<li>Most common (and important) testing is A/B - with the least common (but still important) being personalisation. Specific tests within A/B that proved to be quick wins included modifying CTA buttons and descriptive text.</li>
	<li>A critical consideration for organisations planning to kick start testing in this area is to define testing roles and to prioritise.</li>
	<li>Need justification for carrying out UX experiments? Get someone in front of a camera and give them some key tasks to perform on your website. It may well be the best justification you will ever have for senior management to take note and listen.</li>
	<li><a href="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/RedEye-MarkPatronJumpPresentation09102013.pdf">Download the presentation</a>.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Using social media to engagement customers and maximise promotions ....</strong> - <a href="http://www.yosushi.com/"><strong>Yo Sushi</strong></a>
<ul>
	<li>An interesting presentation from a brand keen to be presented as fun and vibrant - focusing on buzz building as the primary mechanic.</li>
	<li>Customer service is a critical part of their social presence, resolving complaints on the channel of the customers choice, in turn seeing some great online feedback.</li>
	<li>Using social as a source of insights about their customers, collecting and passing on feedback for various areas of the business to improve the way they operate. This included things like new store opening.</li>
	<li>An engaging campaign involved visiting offices with Sushi at the request of workers - in costume and with plenty of food!</li>
</ul>
The above is a tiny account of the event, as Jump spanned the entire day (with the Festival of Marketing on all week). To wrap up, I thought I would include a video from the final psychology session, describing "social proof".

<iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/uuvGh_n3I_M" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>

You can find out more about <a href="http://festivalofmarketing.com/jump">Jump on the Festival of Marketing website</a>.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>513</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-10-10 15:21:25</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-10-10 15:21:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>attendance-jump-digital-marketing-event</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Attendance at the Jump event included sessions from analytics to psychology, catch the highlights of the event on the blog.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Attendance @ Jump Digital Marketing Event 2013]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1843276097]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[attendance-jump-digital-marketing-conference]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_post_restored_from</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:20:"restored_revision_id";i:542;s:16:"restored_by_user";i:4;s:13:"restored_time";i:1390065548;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[524]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Talk @ Scottish Borders TP Conference 2013</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/scottish-borders-conference-13/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 17:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshep.com/?p=547</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I was asked along to the Scottish Borders Tourism Partnership Conference at the tail end of the year. Whilst there I spent a bit of time talking about digital marketing, with the deck now being made available via VisitScotland.

There are plenty of talks available, so feel free to go check them out. You can grab mine below.

<a href="http://www.visitscotland.org/pdf/BeDigital.pdf"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-561" alt="be-digital-presentation-cs" src="http://calumshep.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Screen-Shot-2014-01-18-at-17.15.18-300x207.png" width="300" height="207" /></a>

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

Download the other <a href="http://www.visitscotland.org/business_support/events_and_training/presentation_listing.aspx">VisitScotland Presentations</a> (Including the Scottish Borders Tourism Partnership Conference 2013).]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>547</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-01-18 17:16:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-01-18 17:16:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>scottish-borders-conference-13</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2140294044]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Agile Project Management in the Public Sector</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/agile-project-management/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 15:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshep.com/?p=577</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Working in an agile manner, after a history of creating bulky project briefs</strong> and requirements to front load work, is a little challenging to say the least. I had a history of attempting to nail long documentation, with the aim of ensuring outputs and outcomes would be realised. However, long development times, a lack of flexibility to change things and worries about launching early were always a common occurrence.

I'm now sketching out ideas on whitewalls, snapping photos, holding short stand ups and working with product owners who have a real passion for the projects under their guidance. We're aiming to release frequently and we're aiming to ensure that anything we do is backed by real, verified user needs - something that <a href="https://gds.blog.gov.uk/">Government Digital Service</a> have really been a champion for over the last few years (Thanks!).

<strong>It feels liberating. </strong>

If you are interested in finding out more, the web is awash with various flavours of agile project management methodologies. Within the division work with, we are making use of a hybrid approach, utilising <a href="http://www.dsdm.org/">DSDM</a> for more robust governance and fuller project documentation, alongside a more <a href="https://www.scrum.org/">Scrum </a>like methodology for the delivery teams.

Exciting times.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>577</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-05-03 15:30:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-03 15:30:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>agile-project-management</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[62]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Working in an agile manner, after a history of creating bulky project briefs and requirements to front load work, is a little challenging to say the least.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[agile project management]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2657961746]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>51</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Revisiting an old favourite - URLs | Digital Mulling, Marketing &amp; Projects]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://calumshep.com/an-old-favourite-urls/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>89.248.60.90</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-07-19 12:23:51</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-07-19 12:23:51</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[&#8230;] away from traditional approaches to product and software development. I blogged briefly about this personal switch to agile back in [&#8230;]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Revisiting an old favourite - URLs</title>
		<link>http://calumshep.com/an-old-favourite-urls/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 12:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[calum]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calumshep.com/?p=588</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[When we embarked on our most recent public sector project, there was a big focus on shifting mindsets towards agile practices and away from traditional approaches to product and software development. I blogged briefly about this <a href="http://calumshep.com/agile-project-management/">personal switch to agile</a> back in February. 

So, where are we now? We are approaching our first alpha release, we have begun sharing some early thoughts over on <a href="http://inside.mygovscot.org">inside mygovscot</a>, we are on twitter and continue to code like crazy. 

As part of our hub and spoke model to content contribution within the team, I went back to an old favourite - URLs. 

<strong><a href="http://inside.mygovscot.org/2014/06/25/our-thoughts-on-urls/">Thoughts are over on the mygovscot blog</a> </strong>

(along with some other great contributions <a href="http://inside.mygovscot.org/2014/07/02/user-testing-in-alpha/">on areas such as user research</a>). ]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>588</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-07-19 12:10:01</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-07-19 12:10:01</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>an-old-favourite-urls</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>dsq_thread_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2856137346]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
